Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we shall see how to create a you are to drive by using our SDM 32 Cubitt mix and the
Kubi e of created a new cube next project to apply here.
As you can see and I'm going to start off by clearing the piano.
Quick over here.
Clap your note and click.
Yes.
Over here.
Like this.
And then this is my microcontroller is the SDM 32 for one one.
And you might have a different version.
SDM 30 to Air Force your one and you may yeah.
You might have a different development board as well.
You might have either the nuclear or the disco board and the differences between the two, because what
happens is we going to configure our you out onto microcontroller.
But bef before the microcontroller is able to talk to our computer for testing purposes, we need um,
we need a USP to, to um, to you to convert.
Now if you have to discover port you need an external USP to you to convert.
But if you have the nuclear abort, the nuclear port does not require this.
So let me show you what this converter looks like.
If you have a disco ball so you can just go to Google and search USP to FTD converter.
And.
Different types.
Different colors.
But what is important is they often have our X and T X lines and we can make the R X line of the connect
of the converter to d t x line of our microcontroller and we can get t x line of the converter to the
R X line of our microcontroller so we can jump a.
Yeah.
And then this side connector USP and then the US because Dell Computer, such that we can be able to
send data from this from our microcontroller to our computer.
Again, this is just for a disco board.
The nuclear power does not need this.
Right.
So you can order one.
If you have a disco board, you can simply search USP to F converter F.
TDA is a very popular company to create this type of solution.
That is why your name is there.
Um, so let's go ahead and um, write the um the you are to remember, it's a twisted arrangement if
you have the chip the way you can.
Actually microcontrollers that t x of our microcontroller connects to our X over here and then our X
of our microcontroller connects to T, X or Y here.
And then you connect the ground to ground and then you connect the PCC to the five foot.
We don't really care about DTI are in S.T..
S fine here.
We don't care about those things.
The reason why for the new CLO, we don't need to connect in a extend or um chip is that it's been enabled
for us through the um, the same method that we flash code into the port.
So P a two MPLX three are the U.
At that we can use on the nuclear board.
That does not require us for X then that does not require us to have an external converter.
So we're going to use these in our experiment.
Nonetheless, I should point out that the uh other us more uh are you out modules are available on our
microcontroller list.
Take a look at it over here.
We have you said one.
You said two.
You said six.
Meaning we have three different sets, modules.
And the reason it is written, you said here is because the full name of the art that we are dealing
with, its full name is actually use it in the use that stands for Universal Synchronoss asynchronous
receiver transmitter.
When we are using it in asynchronous mode, it becomes you art without the s such that universal asynchronous
So that is why we often see you Art.
But when you check over here, it is written us you use.
So let's say P to a click on peer to and see which you artist connected is.
You ought to.
I'm going to enable you art to from here.
Click this over here and mode.
Oh dropdown and select asynchronous.
This what I was talking about because we want to set it as a you art if we wanted it as you sort Synchronoss
we select this one over here you art and you realize that as soon as I selected my T Exline, which
is P two in my our X line, which is P three, I've been selected automatically right now.
Let's take a look at clock configuration, often to generate the the you are clock the um it requires
precise clock configuration.
So the clock source Martis yet in our high speed internal RC, um it's, it's precision is around one
percent.
So that should be fine for us.
I'm going to select H.
S I over here.
You see the radio button was.
Yeah, I've just clicked over here to select HSA, so I'm going to be using this clock source over here.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to verify, um, I'm gonna verify the clock for my for my use
that one to make sure that.
Um, I know exactly the clock.
Um, so to verify the clock for the particular pair, for you have to check the, um, the past.
The perp is connected to cause over here we have the clocks of the various buses.
So I'm going to go to a what datasheet and take a look at the block diagram.
So what does the block diagram of our data sheet.
We don't look at this earlier than we are using.
They use it to model.
It's connected to APB one, right.
It's connected to APB one, as you can see over here.
This is APB one.
And then this is use us two.
Okay.
And we said the Artosis word is connected.
And you can find this on page number fifteen of our wall of our data sheet.
And the data sheet is that documented?
The 149 pages.
The other document has over 800 pages and it's another one with a thousand pages.
Right.
So I'm gonna minimize this.
So we said it's APB, one APB, one lessie APB, one time a clock.
Is that, um, is a sixteen megahertz.
And then we have APB, one per four o'clock is at eight megahertz.
What I want to do is set APB one per four o'clock to 16 megahertz as well.
And the reason I want to do this is because those with the, um, the F zero one, um, SDM two board,
they have their default frequency set with this at sixteen megahertz because I don't want to have any
problems between EF four one one and F force you or one.
I just want to make sure it follows the Air Force Rule one so that people with that board wouldn't need
to change anything.
Cause often when I make SDM thirty two courses, I realize some people still have Air Force Rule one.
And there are other changes that are required.
So because of that nowadays, I just make sure the code is sort of fixed for Air Force One.
And then we run it on air for one one.
Right.
So I'm going to change this here to 16.
This is eight people.
One pair.
Four o'clock.
We can verify that again cause we said a while.
You said two is connected to GPP one.
And when I said this to EPB one.
Okay.
Once that is done, I said 16 hit enter.
It's gonna change a number of things.
Okay.
Luckily, we've got everyone at 16.
This the exact configuration of the Air Force or one.
Okay.
We can continue with our configuration so we can grow to be um and configuration.
Stop over here and we click on that parameter certains over here and over here.
We can set the bar straight.
And this is fine.
We can keep it within here.
The same actually the board rate one hundred and fifteen thousand two hundred.
You can change it to nine thousand six hundred, et cetera.
But we can keep this pretty.
These are default settings, so we really need to change nothing here.
If you want just it to be half duplex, if you wanted to be a receiver, only a transmitter only you
can change over here.
That's data.
Um, data direction.
Right.
So we can leave everything the same.
We can live the oversampling the same.
This is calibrated to a what you call it.
This determines the speed of the data sampling.
And this takes into account the frequency at which, um, why you are prepared for it.
Run it.
And we know that 60 megahertz.
I wouldn't touch it.
Nathan, here we leave this the way it is.
I can generate by coming to generate over here.
And I'll give this a name.
You Art Paulin, because we're going to see how to do this would interrupt as well as DME.
So just give this a descriptive name.
And the two changes estimated to Kubi D e and I'll click over here to generate.
Mm hmm.
So there's a project of clean up a bit.
Um.
So in this experiment we only going to see how to transmit data where you are.
So I'm going to create a buffer without data.
I'm going to create this array here, which I shall call message and a message shall hold this sentence.
Hello from Cuba, Max.
And then, um, we are going to use our you at all.
You transmit API to transmit this data.
And then, um, you can find the information about the API.
Of course, cointel you auto C file or go into the reference manual of the whole drive a library.
Oh driver and library I should say.
So I'll come over here and see how underscore you art.
Underscore.
Transmit like this and this.
This function over here takes for argument.
The first document is the handle of the U.
At the address of the handle which is h h.
You ought to be using you auto module to as it is defined up here.
The second argument is the um, the buffer that has the data.
So we call in this message.
We've created this character a record message.
The third argument is the size of the data to be transmitted, which is 30 over here.
And the last argument is the time out like this.
Okay, so if we, um, if we don't do this onto a board and run, we expect to see this message sent
over.
You ought to another device which is receiving it because we want to monitor the, um, the receive
side from our computer.
We need to download a special program that can, um, sort of receive you, uh, you are data from an
embedded device.
So we need a program such as Terra Tim Party or any of those zero terminal programs.
Let's go to the, um, to Google and get one.
A very good one and popular one, which I use is the terror term.
This what it looks like.
You can just try to download it by clicking on this first link here will provide a download information.
This is terror term.
So I've opened this first link in this tab over here.
When you get here, we'll tell you where you can download it from.
It says, to download the available page from OCD and download page.
So you can click over here like this.
And we are brought to this page so we can scroll down here to download it at the X or the zip file.
You can just click on terror to hyphen for dot e XY to download off clicked here.
You can see it's downloaded because I've downloaded this once, I have this as number one.
So you can just double click and go.
And he stole it.
Go through the wizard and install it.
Perhaps I should just show how that is done.
I suspect this is straightforward.
You shouldn't be an issue.
OK.
So this is it.
Oh, double click to start the installation
and then Umbro here.
So once you've read the license agreement, you can click over here, accept.
And then you can leave everything else the same and go to next.
And then if you have a different language, you can select your language over here.
The next.
And then you can create shortcuts, et cetera.
Then next.
And then you can just click install.
But because I have it installed, would it proceed?
Just cancel this.
Yes.
I want to cancel.
Okay.
I'll close this.
So let's build a project.
This whole cube IDC project I click here to build.
It's Putin.
We have no error.
What does it say?
Over here?
It says we are passing a.
Argument two of the whole.
Okay.
So the reason we have a warning here is because it expects us to typecast this to a U.
Eight pointer.
So I'll put it, Brocket, you end it on this Quartey stuff over here.
That is why we have this warning.
I'm going to click here to view it again.
The warning disappears.
So I'm going to click here to go to the debugger.
I'm gonna select this.
And I'm going to open my terror term when you open terror term.
This is where you find you can either use it for, um, TCAP, IP connection or serial.
What we are using a voice, the serial connections or so like this radio button here in the dropdown
here, I see my SDM 32 board.
Yeah, this is the name it has.
You might find a different name here.
But one way to know which one your board is, is to disconnect your board and come to this dropdown.
If there's a particular one for two missing, you can take notes of the and then you connect your board
and come back here.
If you see it as a neo con port, then that is the new device you just connected.
So I'll come over here and then select this.
Com three and then I'll say, okay, over here.
Then this window, nothing is showing this because we're not running from our debug.
I'll click to run.
And our our system is running no.
Let's see what the track team is feeling.
Nothing is showing here.
It just showed a, you know.
And the reason why that is, is our board rate is not aligned.
You know where you set up, we're using a board rate of one hundred and one hundred and fifteen thousand
two hundred.
But the default setting here is ninety six thousand or nine thousand six hundred, I should say.
So I'm going to change the board rate by by coming to set up zero port and then this nine thousand six
hundred dropdown.
I'll click here.
And then also like this is the port rate.
We set our microcontroller to work at Click.
Okay.
Over here.
And I expect our port to stump speech in some data.
We may need to research the port.
Click this.
Oh, we can't even, um, escape that debark view, since the framework is already flushed.
I see it's connecting back to the deep of you.
Okay.
You saw it.
Hello.
This is it.
And the reason why it appears one is obviously because we don't have it in a while, you know what?
Infinite loop.
So we can do that now.
I'm going to take a while to transmit.
I'm going to cut this and put it in the wall.
One loop like this such that it would keep transmitting the same information.
And I'm going to repeat what my project.
Click over here to be at.
It's it successfully earned an hour click here to go to the Depok you.
And then click here to run.
Oh, you know, you don't always have to run your code and debug for you once you come to debug.
You can exit the debugger because the fermoy is going to be flushed into memory and you can check.
But, yeah, we can keep this open.
Let's take a look at it.
And we have this running.
The reason it is a bit like this is because we need a delay.
We have to put a delay there to make it to make it flow smoothly.
We even lucky that it is showing in a in a, um, data at all.
Sometimes if you don't put a delay there, um, it gets stuck.
So I'm going to put a bit of a delay here.
Oh.
See how.
Hall underscored DeLay and, oh, just applied, uh, s mistily here like this.
I'm going to come out.
And then I'm going to click here to build.
And then I'm going to go to the debugger by clicking on the bug over here.
Once that is done or click here to run, let's see what or terror I'm showing, I can see this is it.
It's printed in print and with Tenements Didley, we can increase the font size by coming over here.
Edit I see.
Well, we can just go to set up and then no phone to here and then Fonte.
And, um, we can select size 14 and I'm going to choose this font, Lucita, and then.
Okay.
And as you can see, we have this bigger.
So this is how to transmit data with a U at this or the risk.
If you have any questions at all, just let me know in the Q&A area and I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.